<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ideas on Leandro Ordóñez Ante</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ideas on Leandro Ordóñez Ante</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 14:10:33 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interactive querying for spatiotemporal data with Kafka Streams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ideas/interactive-querying-kafka-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 14:10:33 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ideas/interactive-querying-kafka-streams/</guid>
      <description>Data Pipeline by xkcd.com&#xA;In a previous post we explored a method for performing continuous aggregation on a stream of sensor readings using the Kafka Streams DSL. This time I want to share with you kafka-streams-pipeline, a Kafka Streams application that leverages said continuous aggregation method and defines a complete stream processing pipeline, which enables querying the continuous data summaries stored into a materialized KTable, by incorporating the spatial and temporal dimensions of the sensor data to the analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mocking sensor data generator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ideas/mocking-sensor-data-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 11:44:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ideas/mocking-sensor-data-generator/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Thor Alvis on Unsplash&#xA;In case you are ever in need of some toy data to get you started with a data project, or just to test your ideas or implementations, I think you might find the Docker setup in this repo useful. It allows generating synthetic sensor readings of geolocated temperature data, and posting each record to a Kafka topic. The readings generated follow the format specified in the sample records below:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common procedures and troubleshooting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ideas/common-procedures-and-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 20:29:41 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ideas/common-procedures-and-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Lieve Ransijn on Unsplash&#xA;This is a &amp;ldquo;curated&amp;rdquo; list of pointers I have found handy during my long coding sessions (a major part of which I still spend yak shaving someone else&amp;rsquo;s code).&#xA;Angular related: Link to heading Reloading current route in Angular 5 / Angular 6 (reload component when clicking browser&amp;rsquo;s back button) Angular material datatable example (sortable, selectable and filterable) Angular material checkbox + forms example How to prevent robots from crawling an Angular application ng-number-picker Python Dev and Data analysis: Link to heading Matplotlib: Save images in high quality (EPS, PDF) Matplotlib: Prevent plot labels from getting cut off when saving them Matplotlib: How to put the legend out of the plot Matplotlib: Reverse the order of legend Matplotlib: Read the data and plotting with multiple markers Matplotlib: Using matplotlib in jupyter notebooks — comparing methods and some tips (%matplotlib &amp;lt;&amp;gt;) python re: Non-capturing groups pip 10 and apt: How to avoid “Cannot uninstall X” errors for distutils packages scipy &amp;amp; scikit-learn: How to calculate Silhouette Score of the scipy&amp;rsquo;s fcluster using scikit-learn silhouette score?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous aggregation in Kafka Streams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ideas/continuous-aggregation-kafka-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 10:45:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ideas/continuous-aggregation-kafka-streams/</guid>
      <description>Lago el Bolsón in Popayán, Colombia, my home town :)&#xA;In this post I show a method to address the computation of the arithmetic mean of an stream of values (say sensor readings) using the Kafka Streams DSL. The estimation of the average in a stream processing setting implies keeping track of other two measurements, namely the count of incoming records and the sum of their corresponding values. Let&amp;rsquo;s consider a Kafka streams application consuming messages from a topic to which the readings of multiple temperature sensors are being posted (temperature-readings).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
